Roberto Serra

Senior Software Engineer

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience, during which I have worked with a wide array of projects, teams, clients, and technologies. I'm very passionate about technology, especially with Machine Learning and algorithms.

w: https://www.rserra.it/

g: https://github.com/obiSerra

I: https://linkedin.com/in/obiserra/

k: https://www.kaggle.com/oneobi

Work Experiences

Director of Technology (@ Etiqa)

Apr 2023 - Present

Leading 14 Developers and DevOps divided into small teams on multiple projects while providing technical assistance and mentorship.

Tech: AWS CloudFormation, System Architecture, Lucid, Docker, TDD, Unit Testing, Docker

Software Engineer (@ Etiqa)

Sept 2014 - Present

Designing and developing enterprise and large-scale modern web applications for the US and European markets.

Tech: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Clojure, RabbitMQ, MongoDb, Jenkins, C#

Web and Mobile Developer (@ Muvobit)

Jan 2012 - Aug 2014

Developing and designing web applications, mobile apps (PhoneGap and Titanium), and HTML5 games.

Tech: Yii, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5 Canvas

Web Developer (@Real.co)

Mar 2010 - Dec 2011

Developing and maintaining a live auction web application.

Tech: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Side Projects

Taught a NodeJs class at Turin University for two years
Al and Machine Learning practitioner (LLM, Reinforcement Learning)
Unity and HTML5 game development
Algorithms, coding and ML competitions
Physical computing with Arduino and Raspberry PI

Education

Università degli Studi di Torino

Laurea in Scienze Della Comunicazione - Bachelor of Arts in Communication Studies

Personal Info

Email: obi.serra@gmail.com

Born: 10/06/1983 Based on: Torino, Italy

Skills

- TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C#, Clojure, PHP
- FastApi, Pydantic, Asyncio, Pytorch, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- React, Redux, NodeJs, Express.js, Tailwind CSS
- AWS Lambda, S3, CloudFormation, Cognito, APIGateway, AWS SQS, Google Cloud Provider
- DynamoDb, MongoDb, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Git, bash, ssh, MacOS, Linux, Jenkins, Docker, RabbitMQ
- Unit-Testing, TDD, E2E testing, Cypress, Jest
- Agile and Scrum, PR-reviews
- Very strong communication skills
- Great experience as a team leader and department director
- Excellent problem-solving abilities, capable of finding practical solutions
- Great at adapting to different situations and project requirements
- Quick and eager learner, committed to continuous self-improvement

Languages

Italian - Native English - Fluent